Guide to the Arthur J. Johnson Papers 1906-1993
Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries
Arthur J. Johnson Papers
1906-1993
Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc Terrell Library P.O. Box 645610 Pullman 99164-5610 mascref@wsu.edu http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc
Johnson, Arthur James, b. 1884
Cage.914
0.75 linear feet 2 boxes.
This collection consists of papers related to Arthur Johnson's work as a soil scientist and farm machinery engineer and inventor.
This collection consists of papers related to Arthur Johnson's projects for the Soil Conservation Service, including his designs for more efficient means of planting and harvesting of grasses. The collection contains journals, correspondence, and publications, as well as reports and notes related to Johnson's projects. There is also a large number of technical drawings for the machines Johnson designed.
The collection is arranged in a single sequence by subject and material type, with all folder contents ordered chronologically. Documents for each project are separated by type (papers and technical drawings).
Arthur Johnson enrolled at Washington State College in 1907 and apparently left by 1909, without graduating, when he began teaching in Penawawa, Washington. He eventually worked as a soil scientist for the United States Soil Conservation Service (SCS), a division of the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA). His work for the SCS during the 1940s resulted in an award for superior service from the USDA.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection was donated to the Washington State University Libraries in 1998 by Randall Johnson via Bob Smawley of the WSU Alumni Association (MS.1998.23).
Soil scientists--Archives; Agriculture--History--Sources.
Agriculture
- Journals: Arthur Johnson., 1906-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Journals: Arthur Johnson., 1927-1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Your Land": Soil Conservation Service handbook., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Papers related to a pneumatic seed elevator., 1939-1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Papers related to the Deep Furrow Drill., 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Deep Furrow Drill patent application and related correspondence., 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- USDA Superior Service award to Arthur Johnson, correspondence, newspaper clippings., 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous papers, articles, journal entries., 1932-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Deep Furrow Drill blueprints., Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Vacuum Harvester blueprints., 1947-1951 (Box Boxed oversize, Folder 2/2)
- Seed house and pneumatic elevator blueprints., 1945-1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Grass seed plot thresher blueprints and related blueprints., 1925-1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Seed scalper blueprints., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Art's sharpen shop plans., 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)